CURRICULUM VITAE FOR MICHAEL MATANDA

7560 Borrowdale North

Hatcliffe 2

Harare

29 June 2022

Dear Sir/ Madam

RE: APPLICATION FOR ICTS GRADUATE TRAINEE POSITION

I am writing to you today, hoping to briefly introduce myself and demonstrate my capabilities and

achievements within the ever growing and demanding sector of Information Technology. I recently

completed my Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology at CUT with a keen interest in Software

Development and Databases

I am eager to secure a position with your company and show my expertise. My course has focussed on a

variety of specialist tools such as Algorithm Analysis, Software engineering, Database Systems, among

others as I listed on my CV below. Cyber security, data science and machine learning are some of my

great areas of interest in the field of Information Technology. These have assisted me in broadening my

knowledge and skills while showing me the diverse side of Information Technology that I find

fascinating.

I have gained further experience aside from my studies, through the internship program at (Scientific and

Industrial Research and Development Centre (SIRDC)), the time spent there opened my eyes further to

the creative challenges required in the industry and how it is forever evolving. I rapidly adapted to the

new work culture and team members who became trusted associates throughout my time spent there. This

internship solidified my beliefs in choosing this career path for me.

I am confident that I would be an appreciated and welcome asset to your company and I hope that you

will give me the chance to interview for the available position. While my attached resume will give you a

strong outline of my abilities, I feel that a personal meeting between us would allow me to explain in

greater detail how I can contribute to your organization.

Yours Faithfully,

MICHAEL T MATANDA

MICHAEL T MATANDA

PERSONAL DATA

ADDRESS

Stand House No. 7560 Hatcliffe P.O. Box Hatcliffe Harare

CELL

: +263782892283 : +263772128970

Email

michaelmatanda7@gmail.com

DATE OF BIRTH 07-03-97

ID NUMBER 63-2011413-B66

PLACE OF BIRTH HARARE

> SEX MALE

MARITAL STATUS
SINGLE

NATIONALITY ZIMBABWEAN

RELIGION CHRISTIANITY

Professional Summary

A resourceful, and enthusiastic technologist who has extensive experience of having a wide level of general responsibilities for developing new and improving existing computer-based technologies systems and solutions. A strong communicator with excellent interpersonal skills and knowledge in various fields of CS like machine learning. Contributing extensively to teamwork and always displays a willing and helpful manner when resolving, analyzing, and investigating various ICT technologies.

Career Objectives

To occupy a position of responsibilities that will give me the scope for independent thinking, the opportunity to demonstrate my expertise and initiatives. Developing new and improving existing computer-based technologies systems and solutions.

To be part of an innovative and dynamic organization as well as participating in its positive growth and enhancing my skills and intelligence. Apply theoretical knowledge from college in the real work environment and continue learning and acquiring hands-on knowledge and experience in Computing Science.

Work Experience

Organization Remitech IT Solutions

Position: IT INTERN

Period: February 2021 - April 2021

Duties & Responsibilities

- installing equipment for data communications networks including
- hardware, software, and data communications equipment
- Configuring and troubleshooting network software and infrastructure
- Network monitoring and security checks
- Install configure test and maintain monitor end user work station and hardware Doing network support services to clients

Work Experience

Position IT INTERN

Reports to: ICT Infrastructure Manager, System

Development Manager

Period: April 2021 - August 2021
Organization: Scientific and Industrial Research and Development

Center (SIRDC)

Departments: Network and Support Services, Operations Support

, Data Centre, Systems Development and Hardware

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH & SHONA

PROFILE

I am a dedicated, self-motivated and a hard working young man who gets fascinated with novelty and high internal locus of control with also intrinsic work values. I have a huge drive to take on new challenges and work under limited supervision with a lot of energy, quickly driven by desire for knowledge, along with excellent capability to lead and deliver results on time, thus will enable me to add

KEY SKILLS

value to your organization.

Hard working

Team player

Voluntary wok

Integrity

Punctuality

Proactive

Self-motivated

Duties & Responsibilities

- Network monitoring and security checks
- Support development and implementation of new hardware projects and new hardware installation.
- Work with end users to identify and deliver required PC service levels
- Service desk ticket closing and allocation
- Working on updates and software development project
- Database management and data backups
- Datacenter monitoring and server management

ICT PROFICIENCY, COMPUTER & INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

- Programming skills in languages such as C#, Python, Java,
- Data Science and Machine Learning Model building using Python,
- Web designing and development using HTML, JavaScript, PHP, CSS and J-Query
- Creating websites using content management systems (CMS) like Word press
- Microsoft (Word, Excel, Publisher, PowerPoint, Access)
- Database design and management (MySQL, Mongo dB, SQL Server, QGIS, Postgre,)

PROJECTS

- Automated Speech Recognition System
- Reception Management System
- Help Desk System
- Desktop App: Matcliffe mobile phone stock management system(.Net)
- Websites

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

 B.Sc. Honor's Degree In Information Technology (Chinhoyi University Of Technology 2018 -2022)
 With Upper Second Class Degree.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

- 2 A level passes
- 6 O level subjects including Mathematics and English passes

OTHER ACTIVITIES AND HOBBIES

- Academic and technical research
- Reading motivational books
- Playing mind games

REFEREES

Mr MamombeSoftware Development (SIRDC)0774750930Mr B GotoNetwork Administrator (SIRDC)0774441000Mr ChikwayaNetwork Technician (SIRDC)0776161964Eng.Gweme Director Informatics Institute (SIRDC)0772 419 448

S.Chiminya Software development (FBC Holdings) 0778016526

Mrs Mukubwa Director (Remitch IT Solutions) 0772818829

